Allow over receipt of products in
Business Central.
In Business Central, you can receive
more products than you've ordered from
your vendor or suppliers.
This is necessary because sometimes you
actually receive more than you ordered,
and you want to put these items on your
inventory.
To handle this, we have what we call
over receipt codes.
Let's have a look.
Bring up the tell me search with Alt Q,
and we search for over receipt.
And select over receipt codes from the
list.
Here, I have two over receipt codes. One
that allows for 10% over receipt
tolerance, and one that allows for 20%.
I can set these over receipt codes on my
products, and I can set these over
receipt codes on my vendors.
The most restrictive setting wins. So,
if you have a setting that allows for
10% on the item and 20% over receipt on
the vendor, the 10% will have effect if
you try to receive that item.
Let's see how they work.
Here, I'm on the item card of one of our
products, and I want to be able to
receive more than I ordered on this
specific product.
So, I set the over receipt code.
In this case, I want to allow for 20%
over receipt of this product. I can now
set a general over receipt code for any
product from a specific vendor because I
know that a specific vendor is always
sending more than I ordered. I can do
this at the vendor card.
Let's go to the vendor card.
Go to vendors,
and we select the vendor.
Here, I can also set the over receipt
code.
It's done on the receiving fast tab in
the bottom of the page.
You toggle fold it if it's collapsed,
and find the over receipt code field.
I want to select the over receipt 10
code here because I always want to allow
for 10% over receipt from the specific
vendor. Now, remember that I set an over
receipt code of 20% on the product. In
this case, that will mean that I can
only receive 10% because that's the most
restrictive setting.
One thing to keep in mind is that
there's a default selection of over
receipt codes.
Let's go to over receipt code once
again.
Notice the default selection of the over
receipt 10 code.
This means that if you if you haven't
set anything up on products or vendors,
you will always be able to over receive
10%. And this is a very neat way to set
up how to allow for over receipt of
products.
Thank you for watching.